<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maria Dermit</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maria Dermit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LPDG Proteogenomics</title>
      <link>/news/2020_09_04_lpdg_proteogenomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_09_04_lpdg_proteogenomics/</guid>
      <description>LPDG on proteogenomics What a fantastic talk by Janne Lehtio! He gave an overview of the lattest research and resources available from his lab, including DEqMS to perform differential protein expression from qproteomics data, improved version of the limma approach, as well as the familiar papers on proteome subcellular localization and breast cancer proteome landscape beautifully summarised using shiny apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBI</title>
      <link>/blog/dbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dbi/</guid>
      <description>SQL Server Database connections with DBI library(DBI) #to connect to database library(dplyr) #to do data wrangling library(dbplyr) #the database backend for dplyr library(NHSRdatasets) #NHS data This is a short post that shows an example how to get data from SQL Servers t R analyse in R. This becomes handy when you are analysing data that lifes on a relational database, rather than on your computer. The to-go packages to do this are DBI (DBI)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer-related preprints during the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
      <link>/blog/cancer-related-preprints-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cancer-related-preprints-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on cancer-related preprints. It may seem evident that preprints have served as an unprecedent way of communicating scientific results during COVID-19 pandemic. I recently found a very interesting paper that investigates the attributes of COVID-19 preprints (including preprinting and publishing behaviour) and the impact of the pandemic on the scientific publishing landscape published in bioarxiv. After seeing this paper I wonder how much cancer-related preprints were affected during the pandemic ❓</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Classification with CNN</title>
      <link>/blog/image-classification-with-cnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/image-classification-with-cnn/</guid>
      <description>Image Classification With Convolutional Neural Networks In this article I will explore how to build a CNN using keras and classify images. My aim is to learn the basic of CNN, learn how use the tools to build them and use these tools to analyse digital pathology images.
One popular way to do image classification is buy building Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) using keras. CNN is a class of deep learning neural networks that uses a number of filters to extract features from images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of Genius songs lyrics</title>
      <link>/blog/sentiment-analysis-of-genius-songs-lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/sentiment-analysis-of-genius-songs-lyrics/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment analysis on Katty Perry upcoming album Smile. Smile is the upcoming sixth studio album by American singer Katy Perry. It is scheduled to be released in two weeks time, on August 28 2020. Perry describes her last album Smile as her “journey towards the light, with stories of resilience, hope, and love”. According to her, she has gone through some emotionally challenged times lately, and expecting a child could just add more into that emotional roller coaster 🎢.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidytuesday Avatar</title>
      <link>/blog/tidytuesday-avatar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidytuesday-avatar/</guid>
      <description>Tidytuesday Avatar 2020-08-12 library(tidytuesdayR) library(tidyverse) library(tidymodels) library(stringr) Getting data avatar &amp;lt;- readr::read_csv(&amp;#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday/master/data/2020/2020-08-11/avatar.csv&amp;#39;) scene_description &amp;lt;- readr::read_csv(&amp;#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday/master/data/2020/2020-08-11/scene_description.csv&amp;#39;)  Data exploration avatar_summary_chapter&amp;lt;- avatar %&amp;gt;% group_by(book_num,chapter_num) %&amp;gt;% summarize(mean_rating = mean(imdb_rating, na.rm = TRUE)) %&amp;gt;% as_tibble() %&amp;gt;% mutate_if(is.character,as.factor) avatar_summary_chapter %&amp;gt;% group_by(book_num) %&amp;gt;% summarize(mean_rating = mean(mean_rating, na.rm = TRUE)) %&amp;gt;% ggplot(aes(book_num,mean_rating)) + geom_bar(stat=&amp;#39;identity&amp;#39;)+ theme(legend.position=&amp;#39;none&amp;#39;)+ labs(title = &amp;quot;Imdb rating acroos the three books&amp;quot;, y = &amp;quot;Mean imdb rating&amp;quot;, x = &amp;quot;Book number&amp;quot;) avatar_summary_character&amp;lt;-avatar %&amp;gt;% group_by(character,book_num) %&amp;gt;% summarize(mean_rating = mean(imdb_rating)) %&amp;gt;% as_tibble() %&amp;gt;% mutate_if(is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to lab</title>
      <link>/news/2020_09_01_backinthelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_09_01_backinthelab/</guid>
      <description>Back to lab</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPDG on Covid</title>
      <link>/news/2020_07_24_lpdg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_07_24_lpdg/</guid>
      <description>LPDG on Covid </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-bound proteins</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-bound-proteins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/covid-bound-proteins/</guid>
      <description>Motivation to do this exploration A fantastic paper investigating the proteins that bind directly to the SARS-CoV-2 RNA in virally infected human cells has been recently published by Mathias Munschauer group. The authors used purification and mass spectrometry (RAP-MS) to get the proteome that directly binds the SARS-CoV-2 when this infects human cells in an unbiased manner.
I got super curious about these data and wanted to explore myself. I wanted to visualised the protein-protein interaction (PPI) network of SARS-CoV-2 interacting proteins which certainly will contribute to the understanding of SARS-CoV-2 biology better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LPDG</title>
      <link>/news/2020_07_10_lpdg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_07_10_lpdg/</guid>
      <description>LPDG What a fantastic talk by Prof. Lennart Martens on the role of ML on proteomics. If you missed the talk, you can now watch it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XGBoost Phosphoproteome</title>
      <link>/blog/xgboost-phosphoproteome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/xgboost-phosphoproteome/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(tidyverse) library(tidymodels) library(vip) library(funscoR)  Motivation to do this comparison Last year a great study on the funtional value of each phosphorylation site was published in Nature Biotechnology. In the paper, the authors gather phosphorylation sites from 6,801 proteomics experiments and created a reference phosphoproteome containing 119,809 human phosphosites. More importantly, the evaluated with a regression model the contribution of each phosphorylation site (funcitonal measured as a readout of anotation in PhosphoSitePlus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity</title>
      <link>/blog/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/diversity/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) library(scales) library(foreign) # this package allows reading of .sav files library(wesanderson) library(ggrepel) library(pewmethods) #this package allows exploration of Pew Research Center survey data library(emo) # for rainbows and unicorns Motivation to do this comparison Given that we are in pride month 🌈, I came across this article, where it was really great to see increase trend for homosexuality, and not so great to see low accpetance in some regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify</title>
      <link>/blog/spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/spotify/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) library(spotifyr) library(plotly) library(ggplot2) library(ggjoy) library(ggpubr) library(rstatix) library(wesanderson) library(GGally) Motivation to do this comparison It is always a joke in my lab that Martin listens to better music than what I do. I find this utterly non-sense! To demonstrate my point, I analyse two artist Martin and I really like: on my case Rosalia and on Martin’s case The bouncing Souls. I took this information from his lab Spotify playlist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataviz</title>
      <link>/blog/dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dataviz/</guid>
      <description>FANTASTIC talk on DataViz I did not attend to rstudioconf-2020, but I engaged the #rstudioconf2020 watch many of the talks. One of them I particularly loved was “The glamour of Graphic” by Will Chase. As he sayed in his talk, once you learnt certain things, you cannot stop noticing where those amazing trick are not being used, and I find this to be so true for dataviz!
I start from the premise that any plotting should be done with ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020_06_23_BJTL</title>
      <link>/blog/2020_06_23_bjtl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020_06_23_bjtl/</guid>
      <description>UK goverment message In order to know what messages are being twitted by UK’s PM I analysed his timeline. Reporting the most recent 3,200 statuses, it is clear that the number of Brexit messages out-passes Covid-related tweets.
bj &amp;lt;- get_timeline(&amp;quot;BorisJohnson&amp;quot;, n = 3200) m&amp;lt;-bj %&amp;gt;% filter(is_retweet==&amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% pull(hashtags)%&amp;gt;% unlist() %&amp;gt;% table() %&amp;gt;% names() v&amp;lt;-bj %&amp;gt;% filter(is_retweet==&amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% pull(hashtags)%&amp;gt;% unlist() %&amp;gt;% table() %&amp;gt;% as.numeric() d&amp;lt;-data.frame(m,v) %&amp;gt;% arrange(v) wc&amp;lt;-wordcloud(words = d$m, freq = d$v, min.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rblogdown</title>
      <link>/blog/rblogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rblogdown/</guid>
      <description>How I set up this website The purpose of this post is to show the simple steps how I created this website using Github, Hugo, Rblogdown and Netfily.
First I create a new repo on my GitHub
 Then I downloaded Hugo, a static site generator and got familiar with the way the information is distributed across folders. I also realise how important choosing the right theme for your purpose is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mardakheh website</title>
      <link>/news/2020_06_12_mardakhlanwebsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_06_12_mardakhlanwebsite/</guid>
      <description> The Mardakheh lab website is live! https://t.co/9VA5GFg2fn
&amp;mdash; Maria Dermit (@DermitMaria) June 12, 2020  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCI Webinars</title>
      <link>/news/2020_06_04_bci_june_talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_06_04_bci_june_talk/</guid>
      <description>Making ribosomes to translate cancer I delivered a talk at BCI Thursday seminar series on our work on regulation of ribosome biogenesis by subcellular RNA localization.
In this work published in bioarxiv I demonstrated how a RBP called LARP6 regulates ribosome biogenesis in migrating cells. You could watch the full talk (QMUL access only) here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA2020</title>
      <link>/news/2020_05_26_rna2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_05_26_rna2020/</guid>
      <description>RNA2020 On RNA2020 I presented our CLIF (cross-linking and fractionation) method to analyse subcellular localization patterns of human RNA and proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WFH Weekly Bulletin</title>
      <link>/news/2020_05_13_wfh_weekly_bulletin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_05_13_wfh_weekly_bulletin/</guid>
      <description>Q&amp;amp;A with Maria Dermit This week I answered some questions for the WFH Weekly Bulletin 📰. I have been fundraising for CRUK as part of the BCI Running Team.
If you want to join us or donate, please visit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IWD</title>
      <link>/news/2020_03_08_iwd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_03_08_iwd/</guid>
      <description>WomenInScience On IWD I talked with @QMBCI and sayed what IWD means to me
Happy #InternationalWomensDay!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNAUK2020</title>
      <link>/news/2020_01_25_rnauk2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2020_01_25_rnauk2020/</guid>
      <description>RNA2020 On RNAUK2020 I presented our results on subcellular localization of RP-mRNAs to protrusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Maria Dermit and I am a postdoctoral research assistant at Barts Cancer Institute where I work on big data to understand the importance of post-translational regulation on cancer growth.
I studied biochemistry, finishing my PhD in 2017. During my academic research I have worked mainly with proteomics and transcriptomics and analysing published data. You can find my PhD thesis here
The aim of this blog is to write about new tricks I learn about the tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog.
The main purpose of this blog is to keep track of various projects (including Tidytuesday) and news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Yu J, Navickas A, Asgharian H, Culbertson B,Fish L, Garcia K, Olegario JP, Dermit M, Dodel M, Hanisch B, Luo Y, Weinberg EM, Dienstmann R, Warren RS, Mardakheh FK and Goodarzi H (2020). RBMS1 suppresses colon cancer metastasis through targeted stabilization of its mRNA regulon Cancer Discovery (DOI: 10.1158/2159-8290.CD-19-1375)
  Hoi Ting AH, Ogundele O, Hibbert AH, Monfries CAL, Exelby K, Wood NJ, Nevarez-Mejia J, Carbajal MA, Fleck RA, Dermit M, Mardakheh FK, Williams-Ward VC, Pipalia TG, Conte MR, Hughes SM (2020).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>