<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Maria Dermit</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Maria Dermit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurso Rladies</title>
      <link>/blog/concurso-rladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/concurso-rladies/</guid>
      <description>Florence Nightingale El objetivo de este analysis es conmemorar los 200 años del nacimiento de Florence Nightingale una enfermera y estadistica britanica pionera en visualizacion de datos. Para ello se propone analizar el conjunto de datos que ella utilizó para determinar los factores asociados a la alta mortalidad.
Florence Nightingale fue la primera mujer que utilizando las conclusiones de sus analysis logro convencer al gobierno birtanico para que impusiera medidas higienicas que llevaron a reducir significativamente las causas de mortalidad del ejército británico durante la guerra de Crimea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-bound proteins</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-bound-proteins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/covid-bound-proteins/</guid>
      <description>Motivation to do this exploration A fantastic paper investigating the proteins that bind directly to the SARS-CoV-2 RNA in virally infected human cells has been recently published by Mathias Munschauer group. The authors used purification and mass spectrometry (RAP-MS) to get the proteome that directly binds the SARS-CoV-2 when this infects human cells in an unbiased manner.
I got super curious about these data and wanted to explore myself. I wanted to visualised the protein-protein interaction (PPI) network of SARS-CoV-2 interacting proteins which certainly will contribute to the understanding of SARS-CoV-2 biology better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XGBoost Phosphoproteome</title>
      <link>/blog/xgboost-phosphoproteome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/xgboost-phosphoproteome/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(tidyverse) library(tidymodels) library(vip) library(funscoR)  Motivation to do this comparison Last year a great study on the funtional value of each phosphorylation site was published in Nature Biotechnology. In the paper, the authors gather phosphorylation sites from 6,801 proteomics experiments and created a reference phosphoproteome containing 119,809 human phosphosites. More importantly, the evaluated with a regression model the contribution of each phosphorylation site (funcitonal measured as a readout of anotation in PhosphoSitePlus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity</title>
      <link>/blog/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/diversity/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) library(scales) library(foreign) # this package allows reading of .sav files library(wesanderson) library(ggrepel) library(pewmethods) #this package allows exploration of Pew Research Center survey data library(emo) # for rainbows and unicorns Motivation to do this comparison Given that we are in pride month 🌈, I came across this article, where it was really great to see increase trend for homosexuality, and not so great to see low accpetance in some regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify</title>
      <link>/blog/spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/spotify/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) library(spotifyr) library(plotly) library(ggplot2) library(ggjoy) library(ggpubr) library(rstatix) library(wesanderson) library(GGally) Motivation to do this comparison It is always a joke in my lab that Martin listens to better music than what I do. I find this utterly non-sense! To demonstrate my point, I analyse two artist Martin and I really like: on my case Rosalia and on Martin’s case The bouncing Souls. I took this information from his lab Spotify playlist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dataviz</title>
      <link>/blog/dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dataviz/</guid>
      <description>FANTASTIC talk on DataViz I did not attend to rstudioconf-2020, but I engaged the #rstudioconf2020 watch many of the talks. One of them I particularly loved was “The glamour of Graphic” by Will Chase. As he sayed in his talk, once you learnt certain things, you cannot stop noticing where those amazing trick are not being used, and I find this to be so true for dataviz!
I start from the premise that any plotting should be done with ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020_06_23_BJTL</title>
      <link>/blog/2020_06_23_bjtl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020_06_23_bjtl/</guid>
      <description>UK goverment message In order to know what messages are being twitted by UK’s PM I analysed his timeline. Reporting the most recent 3,200 statuses, it is clear that the number of Brexit messages out-passes Covid-related tweets.
bj &amp;lt;- get_timeline(&amp;quot;BorisJohnson&amp;quot;, n = 3200) m&amp;lt;-bj %&amp;gt;% filter(is_retweet==&amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% pull(hashtags)%&amp;gt;% unlist() %&amp;gt;% table() %&amp;gt;% names() v&amp;lt;-bj %&amp;gt;% filter(is_retweet==&amp;quot;FALSE&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% pull(hashtags)%&amp;gt;% unlist() %&amp;gt;% table() %&amp;gt;% as.numeric() d&amp;lt;-data.frame(m,v) %&amp;gt;% arrange(v) wc&amp;lt;-wordcloud(words = d$m, freq = d$v, min.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rblogdown</title>
      <link>/blog/rblogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rblogdown/</guid>
      <description>How I set up this website The purpose of this post is to show the simple steps how I created this website using Github, Hugo, Rblogdown and Netfily.
First I create a new repo on my GitHub
 Then I downloaded Hugo, a static site generator and got familiar with the way the information is distributed across folders. I also realise how important choosing the right theme for your purpose is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>